Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit. I am the founder of Family
First Financial Services, MBA Finance,
I have been working in the corporate sector for 15 years. And today I am presenting to you
a money back plan launched by SBI Life Insurance on 12 September 2025, named Smart
Money Back Plus Plan. Where you get money back from time to time. You
get maturity benefit. There is the benefit of insurance cover.
If you find the video helpful, then definitely like, share
and subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit Trifle FS. There you will also find videos of 10 to 11 plans of SBI Life Insurance
. Where you purchase term insurance policy for children
, you purchase life policy. You take money backup policy. The videos
of guaranteed income plans, guaranteed lump sum income benefit
plans, waiver and premium benefit plans for children
are available on my channel. Apart from this, videos of other companies
are also available and I have created many different playlists according to your needs
. You can also purchase the policy according to that playlist which
will help you a lot in financial planning. Let's start the video and understand
what great features are there in this money back plan. Let's start
with the eligibility criteria. This policy
can be purchased by a child of 30 days to a person of 55 years. The minimum basic sum assured in this will be ₹ 2 lakh.
There is no limit on the maximum basic sum assured. The maximum maturity will be age 70. Here
you are given three options for premium payment term. You can pay premium for 7 years
. You can pay premium for 10 years. You can also select a premium payment term of 12 years
. You can select the policy term from 15 years to 25 years.
If you want to select any policy term like 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20
, you can do so according to different premium payments. Here the minimum premium will be ₹ 00.
You can also take the premium in annual mode. You can also
purchase this policy in semi-annual mode. You can also purchase the policy in monthly mode. In this, you
will also get the benefits of riders. Let's talk about the maturity benefit in this policy.
So in maturity benefit, you will get Sum Assigned and Maturity, Vested Divisional Bonus and
Terminal Bonus. Sum Asset Maturity means a fixed amount which
the company promises you from the first day that you will definitely
get it on maturity. Whether the company declares bonus or not,
you will get fixed sum of assets and maturity. Let's talk about vested revisionary bonus.
First let's understand revisionary bonus. Revisionary bonus means that the company
declares a bonus every year from its profit and this bonus gets added to your policy
. Now in vested revisionary bonus, vested means that once the
bonus is declared, it will be added to your policy and the company
can never take it back. So once this revisionary bonus is declared, you will either
get it on maturity or if there is death, you
will get it by adding it to the death benefit. So once the bonus is declared, the company can never take it back. This is
called vested revisionary bonus. The third benefit you will get is terminal
bonus at maturity. Some companies call it terminal bonus and some companies
call it FAB. It is given as final addition benefit. This is declared only once
and it is declared at the end of the policy. It is either
available on maturity of the policy or on death. You
can call it a kind of loyalty benefit that the customer has been associated with the company for a long time. He has not surrendered the policy in between.
He has paid all the premiums. So in proportion to the loyalty he has shown to the company,
the company declares a terminal bonus as loyalty
and you finally get it on maturity or on death
. Now this plan, whose name itself is money back,
can also be called survival benefit. So how much percentage of money back will you get? When will it be available?
How much will it be in which policy term? By the way, let me tell you that this survival benefit is 100% guaranteed.
You will get it over and above the sum assured. Let's assume that you have taken a policy term of 15 years,
then you will get this survival benefit in the third year, sixth year, ninth year and 12th year
. You will get 15% money back in the third year, 20% in the sixth year, 25% in the ninth year and 30% in the 12th year
. In total, you will get 90% money back and the remaining 40%. Total you will get
The maturity benefit that you get is 130% benefit. So here 90%
will come to you as money back. Whichever policy term you select, you
will get 90% as money back. Suppose you select a policy term of 20 years, then you
will get money back in the 8th, 12th and 16th year. 15% 20% 25% 30% Suppose
you have taken a policy term of 25 years, then you will get 15, 20, 25 and 30% in the 5th year, 10th year,
15th year and 20th year. The death benefit in the policy is sum assured and death.
Sum assured and death means 11 times the annual premium you pay
plus vested divisional bonus plus terminal bonus; these three will be added or
105% of the premiums you have paid till the time of death, whichever is higher among these two, will
be given to you as death benefit. You will get the option of maturity settlement,
suppose you have taken a policy term of 20 years. In the 20th year, you
will get a lump sum maturity. Now if you want to defer that maturity not in the 20th year but
for the next year or after the next 2 years, then
you will have a total of 7 years. You can defer it between 1 year to 7 years
and if you want to take the maturity at that time, you can do so. Or if you want to
take the maturity in monthly mode or quarterly mode or half yearly
mode or yearly mode, you can take it every year or every month
. Or you can take a small portion as lump sum. If you want to take the rest as income,
you can do so. To increase the insurance cover, you have been given two riders
. The first rider option is an accidental death benefit rider. The second rider is Total
Permanent Disabilities Rider. Accidental death benefit means that suppose
an accident has happened and the person is injured in it. Either he
dies immediately or he is so injured that
if he dies due to that accident in the next 6 months or even in the next 180 days, then
the customer gets the full benefit. So here whatever insurance cover you take of the rider
plus your natural insurance cover, both
will be given to the nominee. Accidental Partial Permanent Disabilities Many times it
happens that the person does not die in an accident. He becomes disabled.
Let's say he becomes disabled in one eye. So
he will get 50% of the cover of this rider immediately and the rest of the policy will continue because you are still
surviving. Plus you get money back and it will keep coming on maturity. Let's assume
that four fingers and one thumb are damaged in an accident, even then you
will get 50% off benefit of this rider. So how much
percentage benefit do you get for which body part getting damaged? You can see on the screen
the eligibility criteria of Accidental Death Benefit Rider. So this rider can be availed by a person from 18 to 65 years of age
. Because this rider is applicable in all the different products of SBI
. So here 65 is visible. But
in this money back plan, the maximum entry age is 55 years. So in this plan, a
person from 18 to 55 years of age can avail this rider. If you want to avail the rider for 1 year, you
can do so. And if you want to avail this rider during the entire policy term, you
can do so. You can add this rider for a minimum of Rs. 500. You can avail
a maximum accidental death benefit of ₹2 crore. You
can also add a rider for disability cover of up to ₹1.5 crore if you wish. There is a person named
Anil Rajput. He is 35 years old. His son is Aarav. His age is one year.
He purchases a money back policy from
SBI Life Insurance for his child's future education and higher education . Smart Money Back Plus Policy where
he selects a tenure of ₹1 lakh. He wants to pay the premium for 10 years and
he wants the benefit for 20 years. So now how will he benefit. Let us
understand through the benefit illustration. Now let us understand all these benefits
with the benefit illustration as to how the customer will benefit. How will this
policy work. Here you will see that the logo of SBL Life Insurance
is visible . When you purchase a policy with bonus, some companies
give you quotations through duplicate applications. Where the logo of that company is not visible and the maturity rate
is shown higher to influence the customer. But whenever you
want to see the original quotation, purchase a policy of any company and
see in the benefit illustration whether the logo of that company is there or not. So here is the logo of the company
spl is the name of the life insurance company. Benefit illustration is where the name of the plan
is Smart Money Plus it is an individual plan. Non linked means it
is not a Uli policy. It is a participating plan. Meaning it participates in the profit of the company.
It is a bonus based plan. Plus this is a savings policy. Where the age of the customer is 35 years. He
is purchasing the policy. He is saving for 10 years. He
needs maturity in the 20th year. For which he is purchasing a sum assured of ₹1 lakh for calculation
. Where his premium is coming to ₹19,525.
You do not have to pay GST from 22 September 2025. You will have zero GST in this policy.
If you want to take a rider, you can take it. I will also
explain the rider to you with another example . So now the customer has to pay ₹19,525.
Now here you will see two-three tables. If you are watching this video on mobile
then turn the mobile a little horizontally. Tilt it so that you
can see it clearly on the big screen because you will see very small amounts in this table
. So the first benefit you will see is guaranteed benefit. Then there
will be a table of 4%. Then there will be a table of 8% and then there will be a table of maturity.
You will get to see the table of death benefit. So first of all let us
see the survival benefit in guaranteed benefit. Where you will get 15% then 20% then 25% then 30% in every 4 year gap i.e.
if your sum assured was of 10 lakhs then 15% of it i.e. ₹1.5 lakh then ₹1 lakh then ₹1.5 lakh then
₹3 lakh as guaranteed money back. Along with this, if
the company declares a bonus of 8%. If revisionary bonus is declared for you.
If you see in column number 12, let's assume that you have declared a bonus of ₹ 00, then it
will keep accumulating every year in this manner. This is vested revisionary bonus. That is, once
it is declared, it will keep accumulating. The company cannot take it back. So if
you look here till the end, your vested revisionary bonus of up to ₹ 6 lakh has been accumulated
. Plus you will also get terminal bonus which is called FAB. It
is called final addition benefit. So combining all of them, you see a final maturity amount of ₹ 1,36,000
. So along with the money bag, you will get
the maturity amount. This maturity amount will depend on the bonus declaration. If
the bonus is declared at 4% then the maturity amount will be Rs. 4,20,000 or if it is declared at 8%
then it will be Rs. 10,36,000. So this maturity can be a little less or more but
the money coming back will be 100% fixed and guaranteed. In this,
you will see that your death benefit of Rs. 1,34,000 from the first day increases to about Rs. 18 lakh.
Here you will see in column number 13 and 14 that there is also guaranteed surrender value. There
is also special surrender value. Here you will definitely
get this much guaranteed surrender value. The maximum company declares special surrender value to you. So,
whichever is higher among these two, you get it as a surrender.
I would like to give one more advice that surrendering is harmful. If there is no need, then
never surrender. If any agent is telling you to surrender.
If you take the second policy, you will incur a loss because you
will not get the terminal bonus. Terminal bonus is given at the end. It is either given on death or
on maturity. If you surrender in the middle, you
do not get the terminal bonus which is called FAB and all other benefits also get reduced considerably. Still
, if there is a great need, you can do it. But this is an option. It
is not necessary to utilize it. If you are not facing any financial problem.
The plan is good. If you continue the policy,
there will be more benefits. And you can also take a loan up to 50% of the surrender value.
If you ever need money in an emergency, loan facilities are available on this policy.
Now let's take another example. Where the customer is
paying the premium this time for 12 years. Taking the policy for 25 years.
Keeping the insurance cover sum assured at ₹ 1 lakh. Now here you will see that you are getting the same money back
. ₹1.5 lakh, ₹1 lakh, ₹.5 lakh and ₹3 lakh and the maturity amount will be
₹14,6,250. So you will think that money
is coming the same way. I have to pay premium for 12 years. I have to stay for 25 years. So now you
do not have to pay premium of ₹1,9,000 here. You
have to pay premium of ₹86,432 only. How much is it? The premium will be ₹86,000.
In this example, I have also taken accidental death benefit. Where
I have taken accidental benefit of ₹ lakh which you get for just ₹2250 and
I have also taken Accidental Partial Permanent Disabilities Benefit for 25 years
which is of ₹1 lakh. Its premium will be only ₹550. Earlier 18%
GST was levied on these riders. Now 0% GST will be levied on these riders.
Other benefits and features of the policy. So if you have paid premium for 1 year then you
can take the benefit of RPO. That is, the
benefits start in the proportion in which you paid the premium. In this policy, if you
have paid minimum two premiums then you will also get surrender value generated. In this policy, you
will get tax benefit under Section 8C of Income Tax and if your annual premium
is 5 lakh or less then both the money back and maturity on this will be tax free. In this
policy, both the revival period and grace period, in this policy, the grace period and free
look period will be of 30 days. You will get a revival period of 5 years. Finally, if
I summarize this video, it is a good plan that
gives you money back from time to time on different needs, which you
can use for your children's education or your own family's household expenses if you want to. The insurance cover
also lasts from the first day to the last day. You
are also getting the benefits of riders here. Maturity benefit is also available. The money back that is coming
is 100% guaranteed. If you need liquidity in between the money, then you
can also take a loan on this policy. So if you found this video helpful, then
before leaving, please like, share and
subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit Triple FH. On that channel, I have created different playlists of many different plans
. You can see on the side. If you want to purchase any other plan according to your need
or want to consult me, then you can consult on
the number given below 9909403412. Thank you so much. Jai
Hind.